## Web Application Developer

Experienced software engineer with focus on Ruby on Rails web application development. Staunch believer in programming best practices, test-driven development, and agile methodology. Able to communicate effectively with clients and colleagues. Passion for writing clear, concise, readable code. Possess a perpetual desire teach, learn from, and cooperate with others.

Specialties: Ruby, JavaScript/CoffeeScript, CSS/Sass, HTML5

Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, jQuery
Testing Tools: Test::Unit, MiniTest, RSpec

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite3, MySQL, MongoDB
Platforms: Mac OSX, Linux, FreeBSD, Windows

Other: C#, VB.NET, Java, C/C++, XAML, WPF, WCF

**EXPERIENCE** 

Cetrasoft LLC 2010 - Present

Freelance Web Developer

Worked on a wide variety of web and corporate identity projects. Coordinated concept through implementation, concentrating on backend design, user interface enhancements through AJAX and JavaScript, deployment and optimizations.

Web Projects Include:

Carlos Ramirez III

carlosramireziii@me.com

www.carlosramireziii.me

oneworldbuttons.com - Button manufacturer nobleinsights.com - Industry expert recruitment service quoteboardapp.com - Social network site findcarlove.com - Vehicle matching site

## **Total Computer Software**

2008 - 2011

Senior Software Engineer

Architected and implemented an inter-agency data sharing system using Windows Communication Foundation with an emphasis on interoperability, distributability, and security.

Designed and implemented a mapping system which integrates with ESRI ArcGIS web services to display maps, locate addresses, and retrieve geo-data.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Guest speaker at the EMEA international public safety conference in Barcelona, Spain for an audience of over eighty people
- ▶ Invited to collaborate with project managers and developers to improve and test software for the .NET 4.0 framework at the Microsoft Technology Centers in San Francisco and New York City

## **EDUCATION**

Williams College, Williamstown, MA 2004 - 2008 BA in Computer Science